<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MPL</title>
    <description>interested in technology, economics, and livin in the future...</description>
    <link>//</link>
    <atom:link href="//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Rules For Urban Onewheeling</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“He will win who knows how to handle superior and inferior forces” — Art of War by Sun Tzu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lando2319.github.io/assets/20150725/IMG_0019.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;desk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve ridden my &lt;a href=&quot;http://rideonewheel.com/&quot;&gt;Onewheel&lt;/a&gt; over 100 miles throughout Chicago. I’ve done St. Paddy’s Day, I’ve cruised Boystown, I’ve put in countless miles within the Loop. The Onewheel is a great tool for transportation, you are neither biker nor pedestrian. You are Wheeling… It has a 4–6 mile range, 12 mph top speed, self-balancing, electric powered. Needless to say you should ride to your own ability and always wear appropriate protective gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videowrapper&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;393&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZK9MxN06LJE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay Frosty AKA Stay Alert:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s easy to get comfortable on the Onewheel, but out in the field you need to be ready, always on alert. Unlike a bike where you have potentially 5 points of contact, two hand, two feet and your butt, with a Onewheel you have just two, and to a varying degree based on your stance, dips in the road are clearly felt. Be especially aware of sections of the road approaching intersections where the road is so worn in by years of traffic, it recreates a subtle wave texture, which can appear gentle. With proper awareness, avoidance of troubled areas, and a good sense of the road, this is all manageable. But dips in the road, potholes, traffic, pedestrians, they are all out there and it’s important to always staying frosty.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate:&lt;/strong&gt; The most powerful tool you have is your ability to communicate. Use it to alert people to your intentions. I am a fan of the left arm straight out for left turn and right arm straight out for right turns. Also having an Alert Call is just one important way to communicate out in the field. Once I made a left hand turn without seeing a biker coming up from behind me, out of no where I hear “Yo-Yo”, by the way he said it and the manner in which he flowed through the streets, it was clear he was experienced and his alert call was lightning fast. Practice it until you have it down. Mine is “Ka-Kaaw”, I made it up, it’s easy for me to say. The important thing is it’s loud, and easy to say without any hesitation whatsoever. “KA-KAAW”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check The Weather:&lt;/strong&gt; not just if it’s going to rain, but how windy it is. Unpredictable winds are something you need to be ready for anyways (see rule #1), but it’s worth checking the weather. I have gone through light rain without any issue, but clearly you don’t want to be out in the field on your wheel in the middle of a downpour. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan Your Route:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference of having bike lanes is huge. If the main route doesn’t have a bike lane, consider side streets. The most preferable is quiet, slow, side streets. Next are streets with bike lanes. High trafficked streets with no bikes lanes are to be avoided whenever possible. Being on a two lane street with no bike lane, and getting passed by an 18 wheeler, is really an experience in its own right, and something I don’t need to experience regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain Your Gear:&lt;/strong&gt; Tire pressure needs to be monitored and maintained. The tire is where the rubber meets the road, literally, so check it for troubled areas. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.rideonewheel.com/&quot;&gt;Onewheel Forum&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource for Onewheel maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also checkout my earlier post &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mikepland/onewheel-review-incredible-product-e6d117c050f8&quot;&gt;Onewheel Review: Incredible Product&lt;/a&gt; Onewheel can be purchase off their &lt;a href=&quot;http://rideonewheel.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Note: I’m not affiliated with Onewheel, just a fan of my own Onewheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post first appeared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mikepland/5-rules-for-urban-onewheeling-e7dad5f81e10&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//sun-tzu/onewheel/2015/07/25/5-rules-for-urban-onewheeling/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//sun-tzu/onewheel/2015/07/25/5-rules-for-urban-onewheeling/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Onewheel Review - Incredible Product</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had my Onewheel over 4 months now… it truly is like snowboarding through the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videowrapper&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZK9MxN06LJE&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awesome thing about the Onewheel and the quality that pushed me to finally contribute to the original Kickstarter, was the fact that you can pick it up and hop on the train, step into a store, you’re instantly a pedestrian. It’s far more portable than a bike, and with a 12 mph top speed you can really sail through the streets. With a 4–6 mile range it works as transportation from point A to B, or just cruising around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way it rides and the engineering is incredible. Clearly some very talented people spent a long time working on it. Can’t say enough about the feel of the ride. You lean forward and it goes forwards, lean back and it slows down. You can go either direction on it, although I keep it goofy. It also gives me enough control to handle the high demands of urban riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riding through the streets of Chicago on my Onewheel I constantly hear people’s reactions, “Whoa”, “What is that?”, “does that have a motor?”, and probably the most common, “did you invent that?”. The first time I cruised the streets at night I had three people ask me if I was from the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Onewheel could have ended up as another Kickstarter horror story, thankfully the Onewheel team came through with an incredible product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post first appeared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mikepland/onewheel-review-incredible-product-e6d117c050f8&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//onewheel/product-review/2015/06/14/onewheel-review-incredible-product/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//onewheel/product-review/2015/06/14/onewheel-review-incredible-product/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software and the Art of War</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All warfare is based on deception. Hence, when we are able to attack, we must seem unable; when using our forces, we must appear inactive; when we are near, we must make the enemy believe we are far away; when far away, we must make him believe we are near. — &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Art_of_War&quot;&gt;The Art of War&lt;/a&gt; by Sun Tzu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had finally given into the pressure, a year after graduation my freelance wordpress developer lifestyle was not working with my Gold Coast expenses. I was going to do it, the thing I had been resisting, I was going to get a “Real Job,” shutter to think… I came across a craigslist post, it was from a startup providing Online Rental Applications, they were looking for a ‘right hand man’ no coding experience needed, sounded ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first day on the job I saw something incredible, I saw the incarnation of the Art of War, the ancient book on military strategy. The Art of War will tell you when small appear big, when big appear small. Walking into this job for the first time, after checking out website, I would not have been surprised to see a room filled of people, programmers, artists, sales people all running around working about, but instead it was a guy with a split keyboard and a Python app. He was small appearing big, a mere mortal who had an ability to appear as many. Incredible power, Art of War, epic level power, all caps level POWER. The kind of power reserved for Kings… and I wanted in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next seven months on the job were spent setting up email accounts, setting up blogs, hiring interns, and all kinds of other random startup stuff. The first opportunity I had I enrolled in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.starterleague.com/classes/web-development&quot;&gt;The Starter League Web Dev Course&lt;/a&gt; and never looked back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few years, I don’t yet have omnipotent powers, but I’m getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post first appeared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mikepland/software-and-the-art-of-war-8c929a6c0631&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 05:21:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>//sun-tzu/warfare/2015/03/03/software-and-the-art-of-war/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//sun-tzu/warfare/2015/03/03/software-and-the-art-of-war/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are Co-Working Spaces The New Cubicles?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here in Chicago, they seem to be popping up everywhere. What are they? A co-working space is where people come to work in the same space, these people most likely do not work for the same company, they just happen to be working out of the same space. The business model is similar to a health club in that you pay for access, there is a secure entrance with 24/7 access as well as the perks of workshops, networking, and office hours with experts, they are often touted as a community center rather than just a space to work. The price seems to be between $200 – $300 a month, keep in mind that a entry level office space in some random strip mall can easily run over $1000 a month. As you can imagine this type of setup works well for startups, freelancers, and remote workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems with more and more companies allowing, even encouraging working remotely the popularity of these spaces is only going to increase. In the 90s we had tons of nondescript office buildings housing hundreds of office workers, each with their own little real estate of a 6 X 6 X 6 cube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I say good riddance. Goodbye Cubicles, Hello Co-working spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Blog post written from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1871.com/&quot;&gt;1871 a Co-Working Space&lt;/a&gt; here in Chicago&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2013 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//startup/co-working-space/2013/05/16/are-co-working-spaces-the-new-cubicles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//startup/co-working-space/2013/05/16/are-co-working-spaces-the-new-cubicles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love music, songs often play in my head for hours or even days. Unfortunately if you sit me in front of a piano there isn’t much I can do with it. I certainly cannot create music, at least beyond tapping a few keys here and there. I’ve always been envious of those who could be with a group of friends, see a piano, sit down and just start jamming. How nice it would be to just jump in with an awesome rendition of “Benny and the Jets” by Elton John.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I can do is make a website. Right now, right this second, I could get an idea for the next big thing, I could get something up on the internet, A/B test it, hell I might even be able to create a decent marketing plan so it gains exposure. But I also code for the little ideas, the ones that make you chuckle, the ridiculous ones…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I code for creation, empowerment, and freedom… I code so that I can enact the next idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like someone who plays the piano can create music, I code so that I can create web apps, enact ideas, and ultimately have freedom of expression. Everyday I can ask myself, “What do I want to build today?” This runs deeper than a career, level of income, or anything on paper. Being able to create things, to bring them to life on the screen, this has infinite potential, I said INFINITE potential. For me, it’s about creation, being the craftsman, being the ultimate authority for YOUR specific app. That is powerful, more powerful than any amount of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what drives me, this is why I code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//inspiring/2013/04/11/why-i-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//inspiring/2013/04/11/why-i-code/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Completed The Starter League, Now What?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been one week since Demo Day and the completion of The Starter League… now what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my fellow Starters have gotten hired as Junior Developers, some are looking at apprenticeships, others have returned to their old jobs with a new skill set. Personally I went from being a freelance wordpress developer working out of my kitchen to a freelance Rails developer working out of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.1871.com/&quot;&gt;1871&lt;/a&gt; as a member. Definitely a step up, even with an awesome kitchen like mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I decided to offer MVPs for as low as $500 (for a limited time). MVP or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimum_viable_product&quot;&gt;Minimum Viable Product&lt;/a&gt; is meant to show the potential of a new product or idea without necessarily being ‘Ready to Ship’ or even fully functional. This would be something to show new investors, potential partners, or anyone else who may be interested in the idea. If a picture is worth a thousand words, than an MVP is worth a million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lando2319.github.io/assets/20130208/greatIdea.png&quot; alt=&quot;desk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I am looking for anyone with a Great App Idea who would like to create an MVP. Do you have a great app idea? Are looking to move forward with an MVP? &lt;a href=&quot;http://lando2319.github.io/contact/&quot;&gt;Let’s discuss&lt;/a&gt; and see if it would be a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/29/i-completed-the-starter-league-now-what/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/29/i-completed-the-starter-league-now-what/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Resume in Ruby</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Below is my updated resume, now written IN RUBY. My intention is for this resume to be at least readable to someone with no familiarity with code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like the full experience clone &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/lando2319/5250412&quot;&gt;this gist&lt;/a&gt; and run the file in terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/lando2319/5250412.js&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//resume/2013/03/26/resume-in-ruby/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//resume/2013/03/26/resume-in-ruby/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Starter League Experience - Completion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eleven Weeks ago I began the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.starterleague.com/webdev&quot;&gt;Web Development program&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.starterleague.com/&quot;&gt;The Starter League&lt;/a&gt;. The course led up to &lt;a href=&quot;http://starternight.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt; Starter Night &lt;/a&gt;  where 120 Students showcased their app creations. It’s worth noting that at in this program there are no tests, no grades, no college credit, so these projects serve as both a platform for learning as well as a measurement of our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Adventurr.Us consisted &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dorrancemike&quot;&gt;Mike Dorrance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kittysingsuwan&quot;&gt;Kitty Singsuwan,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/mikepland&quot;&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt;. Mike Dorrance, Started out with a pain point of wanting to take his kids out on fun adventures, however he had no idea where to go or whether or not his kids would even have fun. This was the beginning of Adventurr.Us, a Family App that allows you to search for family-friendly activities by age, then read reviews from the kids themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Adventurr.Us presents…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adventurr.us/&quot;&gt;Adventurr.Us&lt;/a&gt; Family. Fun. Unplugged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lando2319.github.io/assets/20130314/jump-copy1.png&quot; alt=&quot;desk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now we are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adventurr.us/betaform/new&quot;&gt;looking for families interested in beta testing version 1.0.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I began The Starter League Experience I had virtually no coding experience. My intention was to go from no experience to the point where I had enough knowledge and understanding to where I could continue learning and creating apps on my own. For this The Starter League delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step for me is to continue to hone my craft. At the Starter League there was an energy of innovation, cultivation, and creation. Over the upcoming years I’ll long forget about the error messages that baffled me for hours, even days, however I’ll never forget the feeling of working through them at The Starter League Winter 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/23/the-starter-league-experience-completion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/23/the-starter-league-experience-completion/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Starter League Experience - Week 10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As far as the Starter League Experience goes, we are entering into the end of the program. This means preparing for Starter Night (formerly Demo Day), where we showcase our web applications that we have been working on for weeks now. For me this has been revealing of just how much more there is to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point our education is largely determined by the needs of our Demo Day App. Class time has been devoted to AJAX/JQuery/Javascript and other topics that make our app more professional grade. Just the fact that we are getting to these topic shows just how much content we cover in 12 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins&gt;– Mike Land is a Freelance Web Developer who enjoys technology, entrepreneurship, living in the future…&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 06:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/14/the-starter-league-experience-week-10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/14/the-starter-league-experience-week-10/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Starter League Experience - Week 9</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post will walk you through how to create a basic Rails form with Nested Attributes. By the end of this post you will be able to create a form that takes receives input and saves it to multiple database tables. The example given uses a One-To-Many relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements: Rails environment on your computer. My machine has Rails 3.2.12 and Ruby 1.9.3 p362. Since we are not using any gems and the only built in rails function that will be used is “.build”, I anticipate the steps covered here will be valid for many versions to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with this blog post you may want to reference my Github repo &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lando2319/example_of_rails_form_with_nested_attributes&quot;&gt;example_of_rails_form_with_nested_attributes&lt;/a&gt;, I kept my commits nice and clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step One: Create A New Rails Application. From the terminal run:
&amp;gt; $ rails new example_of_rails_form_with_nested_attributes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Two: Generate Scaffold For People Table. From the terminal run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;$ rails g scaffold people first_name last_name family_id:integer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Three: Generate Scaffold For Families Table. From the terminal run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;$ rails g scaffold families family_name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we have a basic Rails Application with two database tables. The likely next step is to create model associations between People and Families. Since a Family has many People and People only have one Family, this is a One-To-Many relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Four: Add Model Associations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Family Model add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;has_many :people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the People Model add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;belongs_to :family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mikepland.com/the-starter-league-experience-week-5-error-driven-development/&quot;&gt;Error Driven Development&lt;/a&gt; let’s now adjust the form to accept nested attribute data. It’s important to note that the form being used is the one which comes from the parent model, in other words the model that has many. In this case Family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Five: Add the following code inside the Family form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=”field”&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;%= f.fields_for :people do |ts| %&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;%= ts.label :first_name %&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;%= ts.text_field :first_name %&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;div class=”field”&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;%= ts.label :last_name %&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;lt;%= ts.text_field :last_name %&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to see the full code see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lando2319/example_of_rails_form_with_nested_attributes/commit/4913f2daaaef5c7403b835db3f2d67551087cdbd&quot;&gt;github commit.&lt;/a&gt; This would be a good point to run the app, if you haven’t already. Start your rails server and don’t forget to run rake db:migrate, then direct your browser to http://localhost:3000/families/new. You should get the error, “Can’t mass-assign protected attributes: people”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we need to make this new data attr_accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Six: Add code to allow for mass-assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Family Model add the following code to the attr_accessible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;, :people_attributes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in the Family Model add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;accepts_nested_attributes_for :people&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lando2319/example_of_rails_form_with_nested_attributes/commit/38a236ab9095d7602f4660ff866fbcaed57b2a0f&quot;&gt;Github Commit&lt;/a&gt;. Now the last step is to let Rails know where to put this data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Seven: Add .build code to Family Controller under Def New.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;@family.people.build&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step Eight: Test and Confirm. At this point your app should be working. Direct your browser to http://localhost:3000/families/new and test out your new nested form. Once you have entered in some data, go to your Rails Console and run “Person.last” and “Family.last”. You should see the data you just created both with the same Family_id. WOW. And just think you were probably considering using a Gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sincerely hope this post was helpful in setting up a Rails form with nested attributes… Happy Coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins&gt;Mike Land is a Freelance Web Developer who enjoys technology, entrepreneurship, living in the future…&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 05:21:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/09/the-starter-league-experience-week-9/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">//the-starter-league/bootcamp/2013/03/09/the-starter-league-experience-week-9/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
